# 哈喽大家好 我是王刚
Hello, everyone. I'm Wang Gang.
# 本期视频我跟大家分享
In this video I'm sharing with you
# 鲫鱼豆腐汤
Crucian carp and tofu soup
# 首先我们准备鲫鱼一斤（约3条）
First, let's prepare half kilogram of crucian carp (about 3 of them).
# 用筷子插入鱼身之后去除鱼鳞和内脏
Remove the scales and guts after inserting the chopsticks into the fish.
# 用筷子可以有效的防止鲫鱼跳动伤手
Using chopsticks can effectively prevent crucian carp from jumping and hurting your hands.
# 取出内脏之后清洗干净备用
Remove the guts and then clean them by washing.
# 下一步开始处理
And cut the fish next.
# 首先在鱼身上面切上花刀
Score both sides of the fish.
# 这一步的目的是让鲫鱼均匀受热
So that the fish gets cooked evenly during cooking.
# 下一步开始准备辅料
Start preparing other ingredients next.
# 准备盐卤豆腐1小块
Prepare 1 small piece of firm tofu
# 切成大小均匀的小块备用
Cut into small, evenly sized pieces for later use
# 豆腐和鲫鱼的比例最好为1：1
The best ratio of tofu to crucian carp is 1:1.
# 这样的鲫鱼汤浓度适中
This ratio results in a balanced richness.
# 准备大葱1根切成小段备用
Prepare 1 large green onion and cut into small pieces
# 准备生姜1小块切成姜片备用
Prepare 1 small piece of ginger cut into slices
# 准备适量的海鲜菇将比较大根的撕开备用
Prepare some white beech mushrooms and tear them apart
# 最后准备适量的香菜切碎备用
Finally, prepare a bit of chopped coriander.
# 下一步开始制作
Start cooking next.
# 首先我们在锅中加入适量的清水开大火烧开
First let's add some water to a wok on high heat
# 清水烧开之后倒出备用
Bring water to a boil and then pour it out.
# 下一步开始煎鱼
Next, start frying the fish.
# 锅烧热之后加入少许的大豆油
Once the wok is hot, add some soybean oil
# 油温6成热之后加入适量的食用盐
When the oil temperature is 60 percent(180 ℃), add some salt.
# 然后下入鲫鱼开中火煎至两面金黄
Then add the fish and fry over medium heat until golden brown on both sides.
# 鲫鱼下锅之后切记不能马上翻动
Do not flip the fish immediately after they are in the wok.
# 否则鱼身很容易碎
Otherwise, the fish meat falls apart.
# 中途翻过来煎另一面
Flip it over and fry the other side.
# 鲫鱼煎好之后加入适量的白酒去腥
After the fish is fried, add some baijiu to remove the fishy smell.
# 然后加入准备好的姜葱
Then add the prepared ginger and onions
# 再下入事先准备好的开水
Then put in the boiled hot water you prepared.
# 接着下入准备好的豆腐开大火煮5分钟
Then add the tofu and cook over high heat for 5 minutes.
# 大火熬煮是为了让蛋白质充分溶解
The purpose of this step is to allow the proteins to dissolve.
# 家庭小灶则需要8分钟左右（水开之后计算）
For a small household stove, it takes about 8 minutes (after the water is boiled again)
# 熬至4分钟的时候加入海鲜菇
Add the mushrooms after simmering for 4 minutes
# 不喜欢海鲜菇的同学也可以换成平菇或者金针菇
If you don't like white beech mushrooms, you can use oyster mushrooms or enoki mushrooms.
# 海鲜菇煮至断生之后开始调味
Boil the mushrooms until they are barely cooked and start seasoning.
# 锅中加入适量的食用盐和胡椒粉、白糖即可
Add salt and some white pepper powder and sugar to adjust the taste
# 最后倒入装有香菜末垫底的盆中即可
Finally, pour into a big bowl with the coriander at the bottom.
# 一道非常美味的鲫鱼豆腐汤就制作完成
A very delicious and nutritious Crucian carp and tofu soup is ready!
# 下面开始技术总结
Let's start the technical summary.
# 第一
First,
# 怕鲫鱼下锅粘锅的同学可以用生姜在热锅中涂抹一遍
If you are afraid of the crucian carp sticking to the wok, you can rub the hot wok with a piece of ginger.
# 同样也可以在热油中加入适量的食用盐也可以防止粘锅
You can also add some salt to the hot oil before putting in the fish to prevent it from sticking.
# 在这两个基础的要求上油温必须达到180度以上
The oil temperature must reach 180 °C.
# 第二
Second,
# 将鲫鱼放入清水中加入适量的淘米水静养几个小时
Put the crucian carp into rice-washing water and let them rest for a few hours.
# 这样也可以去除鲫鱼部分的腥味
This will help to remove some of the fishy taste of the crucian carp.
# 第三
Third,
# 蛋白质在锅中高温的时候分解
Protein breaks down at high temperatures
# 所以鲫鱼汤必须是开水下锅煮
That's why crucian carp soup must be cooked with hot boiling water.
# 低温为凝固
If you add cold water the proteins may coagulate and hardens
# 蛋白质一旦凝固之后会变得清汤寡水
The soup will become watery.
# 且腥味很大
And it will be fishy.
# 同学们切记鱼汤不能下冷水煮
Remember not to add cold water.
# 第四
Fourth,
# 同学们煎鱼翻锅的时候鱼头尽量朝着自己
When frying fish, flip the fish with the fish head facing towards you.
# 这样翻过来的鱼尾才完整好看
This is how you flip the fish without breaking the tail.
# 大家可以看一下成品的对比
You can see a comparison of the fried fish.
# 如果将鱼尾朝着自己翻锅的时候鱼尾会折断
If you flip the fish tail towards you, the tail will break when you flip them.
# 这样煎出来的鲫鱼成品看起来像翘脚的美人鱼
This will make it look like a mermaid with its feet up.
# 第五
Fifth,
# 菇类也可以选择海鲜菇 金针菇 鸡枞菌
You can also choose white beech mushroom, oyster mushrooms, or enoki mushrooms.
# 如果对颜色没有要求也可以选择香菇
You can also choose other darker mushrooms if you don't have a color requirement.
# 第六
Sixth,
# 煮鱼汤最好用猪油或者大豆油
The best way to cook fish soup is using lard or soybean oil.
# 最好不用菜油
Try to avoid using roasted rapeseed oil.
# 菜籽油相比大豆油更黄且有独特的味道
Rapeseed oil is more yellow and has a distinctive taste compared to soybean oil.
# 鲫鱼豆腐汤的技术总结完毕
The technical summary of the crucian carp tofu soup is finished